By now you're probably wondering,
现在你可能会疑问
why can't we just have one version of all the assets?
为何所有资源不只提供一个版本？
Well, let's take a look at this page here.
我们来看看这个页面
So I'm at design.google.com/devices.
网址是 design.google.com/devices
And this page lists all the popular Android devices.
该页面列出了所有热门的 Android 设备
There are some phones, some tablets and even some watches.
某些是手机 某些是平板电脑 甚至还有一些是手表
But as it note, it doesn't list all the devices.
但是请注意 这里并没列出所有的设备
Now what's useful about this chart is that you can find both the dimensions
这个图表的作用是你可以查找屏幕的尺寸（用 dip 表示）
of the screen in dips as well as the density of the device.
以及设备的密度
So here we see some hdpis some xhdpis and some xxhdpis.
这里有 hdpi  xhdpi 和 xxhdpi
As you can tell, there's a huge range of Android devices and
可以看出 这里有各种各样的 Android 设备
they have different densities.
并且具有不同的密度
Now to refresh us about densities, let's take a look over at the Android
现在复习下密度的定义 我们打开 Android Developers 文档
developer documentation at the topic Supporting Multiple Screens.
并找到主题“支持多种屏幕 (Supporting Multiple Screens)”
So down here for the definition of screen density, it says that density
这里是屏幕密度的定义
means the number of pixels within the physical area of the screen and
密度是指屏幕单位面积内的像素数量
it's usually referred to as DPIs or dots per inch.
通常用 dpi(每英寸点数)来表示
We have five common density buckets that you should be familiar with.
屏幕密度划通常分为五大类 你需要熟悉这五大类
An mdpi device or medium density device has about 160 dots per inch an hdpi,
mdpi 设备（中等密度设备）每英寸具有大约 160 个点
device or high density device has about 240 dots per inch.
hdpi 设备（高密度设备）每英寸具有大约 240 个点
An xhdpi device or extra high density device has about 320 dots per inch.
xhdpi 设备（超高密度设备）每英寸具有大约 320 个点
And the number of dots just increase from there.
像素点的数量逐步增加
So with the extra extra extra high density device, and
对于超超超高密度设备（即 xxx）来说
that's three xs, it has about 640 dots per inch.
每英寸具有大约 640 个点
So as the name and numbers indicate,
根据名称和数量可以判断
the number of pixels on screens increase as we increase density.
随着密度的增大 屏幕上的像素数量会随之增多
So as time has passed, the device hardware has gotten even better.
随着时间的推移 设备硬件越来越完善
We have even higher resolution devices meaning more pixels that can fit on
设备分辨率越来越高 屏幕上具有的像素数量
the screen than what's shown here, but for now let's just focus on these five.
比这里显示的还要多 但是我们暂时先讨论这五大类
So in the last course we learned about how we can specify the width and
在上一门课程中 我们学习了我们可以用
height values in density independent pixels.
密度独立像素来表示宽度和高度值
So that means we can say that a button should be 48 by 48 dips in size, and
也就是说我们可以规定按钮的尺寸为 48 x 48 dip
in reality Android would translate that number into different numbers of pixels
实际上 Android 会根据设备的屏幕密度
depending on the screen density of the device.
将这一值转换为不同的像素数量
So how would that work for something like an image.
那么对图片来说是如何操作的呢
Well as a developer you would declare the width and
作为开发者 你应该用 dp 值来声明
height of an image to be in do values, such as 48 dp by 48dp, for example.
图片的宽度和高度 例如 48dp x 48dp
Then Android would make sure that all these images
然后 Android 会确保所有这些图片
appear roughly the same physical size across devices.
在各种不同的设备上大概保持相同的尺寸
No matter if it has a small number of pixels per inch or
无论是每英寸的像素数量很少
a very large number of pixels per inch.
还是每英寸的像素数量很多
However, if we only have a single version of the image,
但是 如果我们只有一个版本的图片
Android may need to blow up or stretch out the image for
则对于屏幕上具有更多像素的高密度设备来说
higher density devices which have more pixels on the screen.
Android 可能需要拉伸图片
Or on the other hand, if we have a version of the image with a lot of
或者另一方面 如果图片上的像素很多
pixels, Android might need to do the extra step of shrinking it down for
Android 可能需要针对低密度设备
lower density devices.
缩小图片
And either way, the image might end up looking distorted or blurry and
无论是哪种情况 图片都可能会看起来扭曲了或者变得模糊不清
that is not what we want.
我们肯定不希望出现这种情况
So we can solve this problem by providing different-sized versions of
要解决该问题 我们可以针对每个密度类别
the same image for each of the density buckets.
为同一图片提供不同尺寸的版本
And this will also have crisp images on all devices without
这样会在所有设备上都能显示非常清晰的图片
causing the Android device to do too much stretching or
应用运行时 Android 设备不会对图片
shrinking of the image while the app is running.
做出太多的拉伸或缩小处理
So to know what size assets the designer should provide there are dp to pixel
设计师要知道提供哪些尺寸的资源
conversion ratios.
他们可以遵守一定的独立像素与像素转换比例
For a medium density device, 1 dp = 1 pixel.
对中密度设备来说 1 dp = 1 px
So if we want the image to be 48 dps by 48 dp in size, then
所以如果我们希望图片的尺寸是 48dp x 48dp
the mdpi version of the image should be 48 pixels by 48 pixels in size.
那么该图片的 mdpi 版本应该是 48px x 48px
Now for high density devices 1 dp = 1.5 pixels.
对于高密度设备来说 1 dp = 1.5 px
So if we want the image to be 48 dps by 48 dps in size, then
所以如果我们希望图片的尺寸为 48dp x 48dp
the hdpi version of the image should be 72 pixels by 72 pixels in size.
那么该图片的 hdpi 版本应该为 72px x 72px
We can repeat similar calculations for
我们可以根据提供的比例计算出
high resolutions using the provided ratios.
高分辨率的尺寸
And as you can see here the xxxhdpi version of the image
可以看出 图片的 xxxhdpi 版本
will be a lot larger than the ndpi version.
要比 mdpi 版本大了很多
But that's because the xxxhdpi device has a lot more pixels on its screen.
那是因为 xxxhdpi 设备的屏幕上有更多的像素
So in the end all these images will appear the same physical size to
最终这些图片在用户的设备上
the user on their respective devices.
看起来尺寸将保持相同
Now let's take a closer look at the pixel size of the images we
现在再仔细研究下我们提供的图片的
provided you.
像素尺寸
So let's jump into the drawable-ndpi folder.
我们打开 drawable-mdpi 文件夹
I'm going to take a look at the son image.
看看 family_son 图片
So I'm going to selected it, right click and get info.
选中该文件 右击并选择“查看信息 (get info)”
Now here for the ndpi version of this image,
在这里 对于该图片的 mdpi 版本
we see that the dimension is 88 by 88 pixels.
我们看到尺寸是 88 X 88 像素
So we'll be showing this image as 88 dp by 88 dp in the final app.
所以在最终应用中 该图片的尺寸将显示为 88dp x 88dp
So the size of this version has to be 88 pixels by 88 pixels since,
所以该版本的尺寸必须为 88px x 88px
one dp equals one pixel on an mdpi device.
因为对于 mdpi 设备来说 1dp=1px
So what does the pixel size look like for a xxxhdpi version of the same image?
那么对于同一图片的 xxxhdpi 版本来说 像素尺寸是多少？
So I'm going to navigate to drawable-xxxhdpi.
转到 drawable-xxxhdpi 文件夹
Find the sun image, select it, and also Get Info.
找到 family_son 图片 选中它 同样选择“查看信息 (get info)”
So we find the image here is much larger, and
我们发现这里的图片大多了
it's verified by the dimensions listed here as 352 by 352 pixels.
在这里列出尺寸是 352 x 352 像素
So what we're doing here is making a tradeoff between the amount of storage
我们这里是在应用将需要的存储空间和
space that our app will need and the amount of processing power it will need.
应用将需要的处理能力之间找到一个折中
So when we provide multiple versions of an asset,
当我们提供多个版本的资源时
the app does take up more storage space but it uses less processing power.
应用的确会占用更多的存储空间 但是却需要更少的处理能力
And remember, for mobile devices, that's a really useful trade to make.
对于移动设备来说 这是一个非常数值得达成的折中点
Because it means our app will run on less powerful devices
因为这意味着我们的设备将能够在处理能力更低的设备上运行
without running into performance issues.
而不会遇到性能问题
All right, now we understand why there are different assets at different sizes
现在我们已经明白为何在不同的文件夹里提供不同尺寸的
in different folders.
不同资源
So, go ahead and add all these images to your app.
那么请将所有这些图片添加到你的应用中吧
Copy over each drawable folder and
复制每个 drawable 文件夹
then add it to the res directory of our app in Android Studio.
然后在 Android Studio 中添加到应用的 res 目录下
So here in Android Studio,
转到 Android Studio
we see that all the mdpi version of the images are in the drawable-mdpi folder.
我们看到所有 mdpi 版本的图片都位于 drawable-mdpi 文件夹内
Same for the hdpi folder.
hdpi 文件夹也是一样的
So, all the hdpi images are here.
所有 hdpi 图片都位于这里
And for all the other resolutions, as well.
所有其他分辨率也一样
Once you're done making these additions to the res directory,
将所有这些文件都添加到 res 目录下后
your app should have these five new folders.
你的应用应该具有这五个新文件夹
All right so now that you understand why there are assets
现在我们已经明白为何在不同的文件夹里
at different sizes in different folders, I'd like you to go ahead and
提供不同尺寸的不同资源 那么请将所有这些资源
add all these assets to your app.
添加到你的应用中吧
So copy over each of the drawable folders and
复制每个 drawable 文件夹
add it to the res directory of our app in Android Studio.
然后在 Android Studio 中添加到应用的 res 目录下